ÖNDER EMRE ARIKAN

Please contact me for personal information such as address and telephone number * Istanbul / Turkey E-mail: oea.works@gmail.com * Web: https://oearikan.github.io

ABOUT

Avid learner with a broad skill set in IT and experience in project management and academic publishing. Keen eye for detail and focus on productivity and efficiency. Proven record for successful delivery of healthcare IT projects in hospital settings.

SKILLS

IT skills

Markup & Programming languages:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, MATLAB, Python

Build tools, Development environments, Frameworks & Libraries: Jekyll, Git, GitHub, Grunt, Atom, MS Visual Studio, Knockoutjs, Bootstrap, jQuery

Desktop applications, Typesetting & Publishing tools:

Microsoft Office, LibreOffice, Google Drive, LaTeX, Gimp, Camtasia Studio

Operating Systems, Virtualization environments:

Windows, Linux, MS Server, Oracle VirtualBox, VMware, HyperV

Relational database management systems:

MS SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL

Human languages

- Turkish, native
- English, advanced reading, writing and speaking (Scored 283/300 on TOEFL in 2006)
- Swedish, basic reading, writing and speaking [jag skojar inte =)]

EDUCATION

Schools

MSc, Boğaziçi University, 2009

Biomedical Engineering Institute

Graduation work: Effects of epimuscular myofascial force transmission on sensory level; experimental assessment by afferent signals received from lower leg muscles (pdf)

BSc, Istanbul Technical University, 2006

Molecular Biology and Genetics

Graduation work: Analyzing adsorption of bovine serum albumin on gold surface with quartz crystal microbalance

Exchange student, Umea University, Sweden, 2004

Department of Plant Physiology, Department of Molecular Biology

Continuing education

Front-End Developer Nanodegree, Udacity, 2017

An online certification program in which several skills relevant to front-end development such as HTML, CSS and Javascript are acquired and put to use with a couple of mini-projects. (view)

Learning How to Learn: powerful mental tools to help you master though subjects, Coursera, 2018

A MOOC from San Diego University that introduces neurological foundation of learning and some practical methods to learn new things more effectively and retain more of what's learned

Introduction to Python for Data Science, edX, 2018

Lists as a data structure, Numpy and Pandas packages of the Python Library and some basic sample use cases

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Past employment

Application Specialist, ISU Healthcare, 01.02.2016 - 22.05.2017
As the regional partner of HIM GmbH, ISU focused on distribution of patient document management systems to hospitals. I led a team of three people responsible for: Product demonstrations and site audits, POC installations, customization, HL7 interoperability implementations at the customer site, handling of internal tickets.

Application Specialist, Evolucare, 02.09.2013 - 07.01.2016

Medical software company with a focus on critical care (i.e. operating rooms and intensive care units) information systems as well as PACS (picture archive and communication systems, mainly used in radiology departments of hospitals). I led the Biomedical / IT team of 3 people responsible for: Auditing installation sites, providing technical pre-sales support, installation and maintenance of the clients and servers, handling internal and external tickets. Within two years, my team delivered fully functional production environments for two major private hospitals in Istanbul and Kocaeli.

Researcher, Boğaziçi University, 01.10.2009 - 18.05.2013

As a member of the Biomechanics Lab at the Biomedical Engineering Institute, I was responsible for designing and conducting experiments, maintaining and operating laboratory equipment, keeping records and writing reports, presentations and journal articles.

Publications:

Yucesoy, C. A., Arikan, O. E. and Ates, F., **2012**, BTX-A Administration to the target muscle affects forces of all muscles within an intact compartment and epimuscular myofascial force transmission, *Journal of Biomechanical Engineering*, *134*, *111002 1-9*. (pdf)

Arikan, O. E., Guclu, B., Huijing, P. A., Yucesoy, C. A., **2011**, Experimental assessment of the effects of epimuscular myofascial force transmisson in the sensory level, *International Society of Biomechanics XXIIIrd Congress*. (pdf)

Arikan, O. E., Huijing, P. A., Guclu, B., Yucesoy, C. A., **2009**, Altered afferent response of restrained antagonistic muscles after passive stretching of Gastrocnemius indicate a remarkable role of epimuscular myofascial force transmission in the sensory level. *Society for Neuroscience (SFN) Conference.* (pdf)

Front Office Clerk, ARI Teknokent, 01.01.2005 - 01.06.2005

Part time office work for a semi-private company that allocates work space within the university premise to companies for R&D activities. My job here was twofold: i) Help assess periodical activities of existing companies and see if they are to remain; ii) Help evaluate the applications of the candidates to make sure only suitable ones are placed.

Internships

SIMMERK, Istanbul, 01.06.2009 - 01.07.2009

Mandatory internship for the Biomedical Engineer degree. Became familiar with how a simulation device that is used to train surgeons. Operation and maintenance of similar devices. The facility (SIMMERK = Simulasyon Merkezi i.e. Simulation Center in Turkish) was a sub-branch of the calibration department of the Ministry of Health's Istanbul office so I had a chance to make rounds in state owned hospitals in Istanbul region and observe how the medical equipment in those hospitals are calibrated and maintained.

DETAE, Istanbul, 01.01.2006 - 15.02.2006

Mandatory internship for BSc degree for Molecular Biology and Genetics. Got familiar with the methods used in a molecular biology research laboratory such as PCR, blotting techniques, gel electrophoresis and eukaryotic cell cultures. I was given a small task of isolating DNA from previously collected blood samples and use these methods to identify the presence of certain genetic diseases and disorders.

INTERESTS

- Speed reading: Took a 16 hour course from ALGE on effective speed reading
- *Touch typing:* Recently started to practice this because it's fun and improves office work efficiency. Currently can type about 45wpm on QWERTY based layouts. Goal is to reach 70+ and add Dvorak to the repertoire.
- Music: Play bass guitar on occasion.
- Sports: Played basketball with license for youth teams of several clubs in Istanbul. Captained Faculty of science and letters basketball team during undergrad. Hiked and camped the first 250 km of the Lycian Way in southwest Turkey during autumn of 2017, a major natural cultural route which spans about 540 km.Play football (a.k.a. soccer) with friends on an almost regular weekly schedule.
- Other favorite pastime activities include practicing new foreign languages on *Duolingo*, reading my kindle, following a mooc that is of interest and plaving scrabble with my wife.

REFERENCES

Available upon request